# RAFFAELE VALENTI

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - PROTECTED CATEGORIES (L. 68/99)

#### **Contacts**



+39 348 469 1962



raffaele-valenti@protonmail.com



raffaelevalenti.it/



github.com/raffitheo



linkedin.com/in/raffaele-valenti/

### **Programming**

JavaScript	
TypeScript	Advanced
Web (HTML, CSS/SAS Suite	Advanced e/LESS)
C#	Advanced
Java	Advanced
C/C++	termediate
Python	Beginner
Dart (Flutter)	Beginner

#### Skills focus

**3D Modeling:** Good knowledge of **Hard Surface** modeling with **Blender** and the use of slicing software for 3D printing preparation.

2D Design and Texturing: Good knowledge of GIMP and Inkscape for 2D graphics, as well as Substance Painter and Substance Designer for creating and managing advanced textures.

Game Engines: In-depth knowledge of Unity and basic skills in using Unreal Engine.

Front-end: Extensive experience with React, React Native, and Ionic, along with a good knowledge of other frameworks and libraries such as Angular and Vue.

#### Work experience

# 2024-11 present

#### Software Developer

Tecnolife IT Consulting S.r.l. - Remote, Trieste

Design and front-end development of React applications.

**Skills acquired:** Development of **Flutter** applications, including the use of tools such as **FlutterFlow**; bases for programming in **Python**, utilizing **Docker** containers for managing and deploying the various environments needed by the application (development, quality assurance and production).

#### 2024-10 2024-03

#### **Digital Transformation Analyst**

FINCANTIERI S.p.A. - Hybrid, Trieste

 Design and development of back-end and front-end libraries to better and more simply manage future updates of various applications.
 In particular, the front-end libraries were created using React and Storybook for the visualization and documentation of graphic components.

**Skills acquired:** Creation and utilization of internal front-end and back-end libraries, with a focus on maintenance, versioning, compatibility, and developer experience.

#### 2024-03 2021-11

#### **Digital Transformation Analyst (Apprenticeship)**

FINCANTIERI S.p.A. - Hybrid, Trieste

- Design and implementation of a complex technology stack, comprising both a back-end and a front-end. Both have their respective environments (development and production) and dedicated release pipelines.
   The solutions were built using React for the front-end and .NET 6/8 with Entity Framework for the back-end.
- Full-stack design and development of web applications in a SharePoint Online environment using the technology stack designed.

**Skills acquired:** Coordination of a development team consisting of 2 to 4 members, software maintenance with a focus on bug fixing and implementation of change requests, execution of user acceptance testing (UAT), and management of the relationship with end users.

#### 2021-10 2021-04

Beginner

#### Digital Transformation Analyst (Internship)

FINCANTIERI S.p.A. - Hybrid, Trieste

- Front-end design and development of web applications without a back-end in a SharePoint Online environment.
  - The solutions were built using React, Bootstrap, and jQuery.
- Development of an augmented reality application for shipyards, designed for 3D visualization of ship assembly plans on Android devices.
   The app was built using the **Unity** game engine, leveraging its AR technologies and features.

**Skills acquired:** Operational management on behalf of a large company in the IT sector, with a focus on meeting deadlines, planning deliveries, and releasing software in production environments.

#### 2019-07 2019-01

#### Android and Web Developer (Internship)

CodaQ S.r.I.s. - In office, Area Science Park (Padriciano, Trieste)

- Development of an Android application integrated with a pre-existing queue management system.
  - The app features a dynamic user interface that can be modified in real time without the need for code recompilation.
- Development of a mobile application for Android and iOS devices, aimed at managing patient access flows at the IRCCS Materno Infantile "Burlo Garofolo".

The application was built using the **Angular** framework and **NativeScript** libraries to ensure cross-platform compatibility.

**Skills acquired:** Management of an IT company, coordination of software projects, and effective collaboration within development teams involving multiple programmers working on the same project.

# RAFFAELE VALENTI

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - PROTECTED CATEGORIES (L. 68/99)

#### Technical skills

**Software:** Microsoft Windows, Linux (Ubuntu Desktop, Ubuntu Server, PopOS, Tumbleweed), Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Cursor, Trae, Eclipse, Unity, Blender, GIMP, Inkscape **Libraries and Frameworks:** .NET, Entity Framework, Node.js, React, React Native, Ionic, Expo, Vite, Webpack

**Version Control:** Git, GitHub Desktop, Sourcetree, GitHub, GitLab, Bitbucket, Azure DevOps **Databases:** MongoDB, SQL Server Management Studio, PostgreSQL, Firebase, Supabase **Others:** Coding Als, Azure, Docker, Rancher Desktop, FlutterFlow

### **Educational background**

2019-07 2017-10 Higher Technician for the Development and Management of Biomedical IT Solutions (TIB)

Fondazione Istituto Tecnico Superiore "Alessandro Volta"

2017-07 2012-09 High school diploma in Chemistry, Materials, and Biotechnology

Istituto Tecnico Statale "Grazia Deledda - Max Fabiani"

### **Notes**

**Recognition under Law 68/99**: 74% disability and inclusion in the protected categories pursuant to Law 68/99 (Italy).

#### **Privacy**

I authorize the processing of personal data in compliance with the applicable data protection laws, in particular, the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) 2016/679, Legislative Decree 30/06/2003 no. 196 and subsequent amendments and integrations.

Back-end: Strong knowledge of C#, JavaScript, and TypeScript, enabling me to work with various back-end technologies, including Entity Framework (for C#) or Express (for JavaScript and TypeScript).

#### Languages

Mothertongue (C2)
French

Mothertongue (C2)
English

Advanced (B2)